[
	{
		"//" : "Copyright 2018 Atos SE and Worldline",
		"//" : "Licensed under MIT (https://github.com/atosorigin/DevOpsMaturityAssessment/blob/master/LICENSE)",
		"SectionName" : "Introduction",
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Banner",
				"QuestionText" : "The goal of this questionaire is to help you assess the DevOps maturity of your team and to help you understand what might be the appropriate next steps for you on your DevOps journey.<br><br>These questions are intended to be completed for one team (typically reporting to the same line manager and usually consisting of between 5 and 15 people)."
			}
		]
	},
	{
		"SectionName" : "Team Agility",
		"SpiderPos" : 2,
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team releasing a new, potentially shippable version of the product every 1-2 weeks?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Checkbox",
				"QuestionText" : "What are the metrics measured by the team?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Elapsed time between delivering valuable improvements (from initial request to production)", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Frequency of production deployments", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Modification in the failure rate", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Time to re-establish service after a failure", "Score" : 0.5}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team meeting on a frequent basis to discuss what is working well, what isn't working well, and what may be improved, and are the top improvement items implemented?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team taking steps to avoid creating or experiencing bottlenecks with/for other teams?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, and the measures are effective", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, but the actions are not always beneficial.", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Do employees work together to resolve any work items that get halted?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a well-defined procedure for determining the priority of the backlog?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the team prioritize the backlog according to the priority?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Are the most experienced team members assigned last so that they can assist others in developing cross-functional abilities while remaining free to focus on the most business essential or complex problems?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Checkbox",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a fast feedback loop in place on the team?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "From testers: usually less than 1 day", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "From the product owner: usually less than 3 days", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "From customers: usually less than 2 weeks", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "From end users: usually less than 2 weeks", "Score" : 0.5}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Are proactive actions being done to reduce reliance on 'super heroes' (e.g., pair programming, mob learning, real options)?"
			}
		]
	},
	{
		"SectionName" : "Collaboration",
		"SpiderPos" : 7,
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Are knowledge and interests shared inside the team and across the organisation (for example, through communities of interest)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, but only within the team", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 1}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a method for asynchronous communication in place (for example, Kanban Board, JIRA, Slack, Circuit)?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Do team members have mechanisms in place to collaborate with others outside the team?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is everyone on the team willing to work on projects that aren't in their area of expertise?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "This is something that everyone in the team is willing to do", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Some members of the team are willing to do so", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "People in the team, on the whole, prefer not to do this", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Do team members prefer the most immediate (information-rich) communication mode available (e.g., voice call rather than email)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Everyone on the team does", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Most people on the team do", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Most people on the team do not", "Score" : 0}
					]					
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there enough opportunity for team members to meet face to face?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "How frequently do misunderstandings occur among team members?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Hardly ever", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Fairly frequently (at least once per week)", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Very frequently (at least once per day)", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Are team members' ideas/concerns shared with the rest of the team, and are they fairly represented?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, always", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, most of the time", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Hardly ever", "Score" : 0}
					]
			}
		]
	},
	{
		"SectionName" : "Automation",
		"SpiderPos" : 3,
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Environments",
				"QuestionText" : "Are the environments used for development and testing consistent with those used for production?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is infrastructure provisioning, configuration, and administration (e.g., networks, storage, etc.) automated (for example, through the use of Infrastructure as Code)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Partially", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Checkbox",
				"SubCategory" : "Environments",
				"QuestionText" : "For which of these is environment configuration and management automated (check all that apply)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Virtual machines", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Networks", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Operating systems", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Security elements", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "The application stacks", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "The applications", "Score" : 0.5}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Environments",
				"QuestionText" : "Are the appropriate environments (e.g., dev, test, integration) available on demand (i.e., at the right time or in a method that does not cause activities to be delayed)?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Environments",
				"QuestionText" : "Is environment provisioning, configuration, and management automated?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, and scaling is automatic", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, but scaling is manual", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Testing",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a high level of automated integration testing in place (testing the interaction of modules with one another) within the team?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and are executed on each build", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, there are automatic tests in place", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Testing",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a high level of automated system testing in place (to ensure overall system functionality fulfils requirements)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and are executed on each build", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, there are automatic tests in place", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Testing",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a high level of automated performance testing in place on the team?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and are executed on each build", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, there are automatic tests in place", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Testing",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the team complete automated scanning of source code assets?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and are executed on each build", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, there are automatic tests in place", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Static Analysis",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team finished using automatic binary scanning?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and are executed on each build", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, there are automatic tests in place", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Static Analysis",
				"QuestionText" : "Is code checked for quality automatically throughout the build process?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and are executed on each build", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, there are automatic tests in place", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a break in the build if coding standards or security rules are not met?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is automation code produced with the same rigour as product code (for example, testing and source control)?"
			}			
		]
	},
	{
		"SectionName" : "Architecture and Design",
		"SpiderPos" : 5,
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the architecture of the application comprise of loosely associated components (choose the most relevant scenario)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "The application is built from a number of stateless components with scaling and resilience provided at the application layer (full MicroServices)", "Score" : 3},
					{"Answer" : "The application is made up of several separate components but relies on external solutions to provide availability and scalability", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "The application is largely monolithic but made up of code modules that can be worked on independently and then re-compiled into a single unit", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "The application is built up of monolithic code and can only be changed in its entirety as part of a release schedule", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Checkbox",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the architecture allow the development, testing and other QA activities to be prototypical and execute autonomously of each another without impacting production (tick all that apply)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "There are fully separate development, test and QA environments", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Environments are regularly re-built or synchronised (at least monthly)", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "The 3 environments are similar at all levels (resilience, performance, security, dependencies)", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Each environment can be torn down and rebuilt without affecting other environments", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : " Environment specific configuration items are decoupled from the code in order to accelerate rebuilds", "Score" : 0.5}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the architecture allow the deployment of services autonomously of one another?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, every element of functionality can be updated individually and applied to the application", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "Partially, some elements can be updated independently, but there are certain core components that need to be updated together in order to maintain functionality", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "No, updates to the system need to be performed together in a formal release cycle", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Are all application logs put down on a central log repository automatically with the configuration included in the environment design to allow flexibility between environments?"
			}
		]
	},
	{
		"SectionName" : "DevOps Practices",
		"SpiderPos" : 6,
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Checkbox",
				"SubCategory" : "CI",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the team control their source code in a principal source control system (tick all that apply)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "We have a common code repository (e.g. Git based repo)", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "We have a defined branching structure", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "We have defined repository structure", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Our structure and branching strategy are aligned to our Dev, Test, and Prod environments (enabling a smooth flow between environments)", "Score" : 0.5}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "CI",
				"QuestionText" : "How often does developers incorporate their changes into a common mainline (trunk)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Code is integrated at least once per day", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "Code is integrated at least weekly", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Code is integrated infrequently but at least once a month", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Code is integrated on an ad hoc basis when the developer feels it is ready to share", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Code Review",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a specific code review and approval procedure?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "We have a targeted code review process that is appropriate and ensures code is published in a timely manner", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "We have a code review process but the process incurs delays and hinders deployments", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "We have no code review process and bugs can frequently be integrated into the mainline (trunk)", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "CD",
				"QuestionText" : "Whenever code is incorporated with a common mainline (trunk), are automated processes initiated?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, an automated build of the software is triggered into a production-like environment, automated tests are then triggered and software is available to be automatically deployed into production", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, an automated build of the software is triggered into a production-like environment, manual tests are then performed before the release is manually deployed into production", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, an automated build of the software is triggered, however this build is then manually deployed into the relevant environments (QA and Prod)", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "CI",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there always a prior escalation to fix a broken build?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, builds are fixed / rolled back within 10 minutes", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, builds are fixed / rolled back  within 1 hour", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, builds are fixed / rolled back  within a day", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "CI",
				"QuestionText" : "Are enough notifications incorporated to communicate the build status and failures to the team (e.g. automated e-mails, slack, circuit)?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "CD",
				"QuestionText" : "Is it possible to abolish the application cleanly and reliably?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Refactoring",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the team do regular restructuring of their code?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Refactoring",
				"QuestionText" : "Is time given to restructuring in order to improve code quality and reduce technical debt?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Refactoring",
				"QuestionText" : "Are there enough automated tests in place to enable developers to restructure with confidence?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "TDD",
				"QuestionText" : "How often does the team practice Test Driven Development (TDD), making sure that automated tests are developed in advance of new features?", 
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "All product code is developed using TDD", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "Some product code is developed using TDD", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "TDD is not used at all", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "TDD",
				"QuestionText" : "Is a standard test framework (such as JUnit) used by the team?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "TDD",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the refactoring step of the TDD cycle usually applied?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "TDD",
				"QuestionText" : "Are mocks/stubs/simulators used to ensure that tests can be run quickly, frequently and repeatably?"
			}
		]
	},
	{
		"SectionName" : "Org Structure, Culture and Incentives",
		"SpiderPos" : 1,
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the delivery team cross functional, incorporating development, testing and operations competency?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
				"QuestionText" : "The incentives for people on the team (both financial and non-financial) is based on overall team results?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
				"QuestionText" : "Are the people responsible for designing, developing, testing and operating the application in the same team?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team liable for the product throughout its life-cycle (introduction, growth, maturity, decline)?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Culture",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team motivated to do new experiments and innovate?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Culture",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a reliable trust culture which empowers independence?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
				"QuestionText" : "Do people working on developing and running the application work towards same incentives and goals?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the team have an authority in what they work on (e.g. self selection days)?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
				"QuestionText" : "Does the organisation's structure catalyse and support a DevOps approach?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a team authorized that sets out on how the team behaves and works along?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
				"QuestionText" : "Is there a clarity in the vision and purpose of the product?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Are all stakeholders identified and engaged for the product?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team provocated and oriented towards a measurable business outcome?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "Do management and the whole organisation realize the importance of protecting time for continuous evolution?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "can the team involve in learning new technologies, tools and practices?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
				"QuestionText" : "How frequently does the business and the development team interact?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Business users are embedded within the team", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "The team meets with the business at least every week", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "The team meets with the business at least every month", "Score" : 0.5},
					{"Answer" : "Rarely or not at all", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Culture",
				"QuestionText" : "Are the superior stakeholders liberal and support the DevOps approach?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, we rarely have issues with business cases or bureaucratic processes", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Culture",
				"QuestionText" : "Are the team members involved in continuous learning?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"SubCategory" : "Culture",
				"QuestionText" : "Is the team open to having a feedback (where people are encouraged to promptly share negative and positive feedback)?"
			}
		]
	},
	{
		"SectionName" : "Standardisation",
		"SpiderPos" : 5,
		"Questions" : [
			{
				"Type" : "Checkbox",
				"QuestionText" : "On a set of tooling standards, how is the organisation standardised (tick all that apply)?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "We have a defined set of CI/CD tooling that is universally used", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "We have defined code repository tooling and standardised usage processes for them (e.g. branching pattern)", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "We have defined monitoring tooling", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "We have defined patching/upgrade tooling and processes (e.g. immutable vs. mutable)", "Score" : 1}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "On a set of application stacks/development languages, how is the organisation standardised ?",
				"Answers" : [
					{"Answer" : "Yes, with a sufficient portfolio of options to meet our development needs", "Score" : 2},
					{"Answer" : "Yes, but with an insufficient portfolio of options to meet our development needs", "Score" : 1},
					{"Answer" : "No, any team can choose any stack/language without constraint", "Score" : 0}
					]
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "In case of utility applications do you make the best use of SaaS (Software as a Service) (i.e. ones not used for competitive advantage such as version control)?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "However much checks out, do you utilize PaaS (Platform as a Service)?"
			},
			{
				"Type" : "Option",
				"QuestionText" : "However much checks out, do you utilize IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service)?"
			}
		]
	}
]	